

Christofer Ryås christofer.ryas@ gmail.com (+46) 070-3419082

Christofer Ryås

Master of Science, Engineering Physics

About me After five years working offshore in the oil and gas industry I took a programming course in C#.NET during the spring of 2018 in order to complement my masters degree in Engeneering Physics. This gives me a good combination of problem solving and physiscs knowledge combined with understanding of programming and software development. My experience working with co-workers from all over the world and with a wide range of educational background, together with my theoretical education, makes me a valuable asset in many different areas. I am also a quick learner and good at adopting to new situations.

Experience

Nov 2016 - Jan 2018, Seismic observer¹, Shearwater Geophysical AS

Online monitoring of seismic data and maintenance of seismic equipment both onboard and at sea. Writing, editing and following QHSE procedures. Working in for example India, Oman and Ireland.

June 2012 - Dec 2015, Seismic observer, Dolphin Geophysical AS

Online monitoring of seismic data and maintenance of seismic equipment both onboard and at sea. Writing, editing and following QHSE procedures. Working in Australia, Singapore, Myanmar, Colombia and Europe.

May 2009 - June 2010, Student pub manager, Kårhuset Origo

Responsible for the daily operations, including receiving bookings and sending orders. I was also in charge of the voluntary workers, their education and making sure laws and regulations were followed.

Education

Jan 2018 - Apr 2018, C#.NET VT18, Academy

A 12-week intensive course in C#.NET held by Academy, a part of Academic Work. The course focused mainly on C#.NET but also included for example SQL, JavaScript and Agile Development.

Sep 2017 - Jan 2018, Master Thesis, Photon Sports

Title: Improving repeatability and comparability in sports training using a 3D-camera.

Sep 2005 - Jan 2012, Master of Science in Engineering Physics, Umeå University

Major in measurement techniques and computational physics. I've taken advanced courses in for example *Physical Properties of Measurement Devices* and *Non-invasive Measurement Methods*.

¹Marine seismic is a method to look at the Earth's properties under the sea bed to find potential areas for oil and gas production. Our clients were often the big oil companies. Typically I worked on a five week rotation, working 12 hours a day when onboard. My department were responsible for the measurement equipment as well as monitoring the data online as it was acquired. The work duties varied a lot though since everyone have to help the other departments out whenever they don't have time or manpower enough to fix a certain task in time. Safety is a big concern in the whole offshore industry and every task onboard has it's own procedure and risk assessment. Everyone onboard must follow these procedures and it's a part of the job to be involved in writing new procedures as well as updating old ones.

Skills

Languages

Swedish (Native)

Computer software

- o C#
- SQL
- JavaScript

- English (Fluent)
- Unit Testing
- Matlab
- Microsoft Office

Courses & Certificates

- Scrum PSM1
- Basic Safety Training incl. HUET
- o G20 Fixed Hydr Crane
- Work Boat Crew Member

Other skills and competences

Multicultural Competency

During my years offshore I've worked on four different vessels and in several countries in Europe, Africa, South America, Asia and Australia. The crews have always been a mixture from different countries, cultures and educational background.

Competitive

I've always been very competitive and hate to lose. I will always try to make a task as good and as efficient as possible, both in everyday life and work tasks. In my free time I practice, coach and compete in table tennis.

Management skills

During my year as a student pub manager I was in charge of about a hundred voluntary workers, making sure they followed all the rules and regulations. I also had to make sure the work environment was good enough to motivate the students to come and work again.

Works well under pressure

I've always been calm and don't get stressed easily. This was something I had good use of in my previous job where the days usually were either very calm or very busy.

Driver's License since 2005